hi my name is Byron Udell I'm the
founder and CEO of accuquote.com the
question today is how to cash in my
credential life
insurance simple answer you contact the
company and let them know you want to
surrender the policy if the policy was
the kind that actually has a cash value
you'll be given a form it can probably
be faxed or emailed to you you fill out
a simple form and if you are the owner
of the policy which is the only person
that has the right to do anything with
the policy while you're still here um
all you need to do is fill out that form
send it to them it's called a surrender
form they will send you what if any cash
value was in the policy typically term
policies have no cash value whole life
and Universal Life policies often do
have cash value and that's how you would
cash them in if the question was more
toward how to make a claim a death claim
or sort cash in a life insurance policy
after the death of the insured that's
the ordinary claims process and is the
culmination of what life insurance is
all about you would just submit a death
claim form and to do that you would need
a death certificate and some sort of
proof that you're the Ben you know that
you are the person that's listed they'll
know who the beneficiary of record is
you just need to prove that you are that
person typically either way the process
is very very quick it only takes a few
days if a death claim comes in um it may
take a week or two unless the policy is
fresh and and if the policy is again if
the policy is new uh the policy may take
a little bit longer to pay just so the
carrier has time to to investigate
whether or not there was any kind of
fraud in the inducement or fraud in the
in the acquiring of the policy but
cashing in an existing policy if you're
alive very simple process just contact
the carrier and they'll tell you what
the cash surrender value is send you a
simple form you fill it out you get your
check your policy's gone you got your
money and you're done hope this was
helpful again my name is Byron Udell
I am the founder and CEO of
accuquote.com